A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Knowledge, Creativity and Freedom, Media, Arts, and Culture, Media Unit, Office Files of Becky Lentz FA1426
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Grant Files, 1998-2007; 1
  - Syracuse University (1 of 2), 2001-2002 (Box 11, Folder 73)
    Correspondence; Draft - Digital Media Forum: Mapping the Public Interest Communication Policy Field, A Research Proposal to the Ford Foundation, Media Policy Program Lewis A. Friedland; Can Ford Have Better Ideas? Toward a New Agenda in Communications and Technology Policy, Dr. Milton Mueller; Reinviting Media Activism; Report - Reinventing Media Activism: Local and Transnational Action and the Globalization of the Media, Dr. Milton Mueller; Interest Groups and the Public Interest: Civil Society Action and the Globalization of Communication Policy
  - Syracuse University (2 of 2), 2003 (Box 12, Folder 74)
    Correspondence; Preliminary Review Draft - Reinventing Media Activism: Citizen Activism as a Socio-Economic and Political Phenomenon, Milton Mueller; Cheryl Leanza - Reactions to Milton's paper
  - Telecommunications Policy Research Conference, 2000-2002 (Box 12, Folder 75)
    Grant Nos.: 10000504 and 10150486 - correspondence; Report of TPRC, Inc. Program Year 2000; TPRC Presents the 28th Annual Research Conference on Information, Communications, and Internet Policy: A Proposal to the Ford Foundation; TRPC Presents the 29th Annual Research Conference on Information, Communications, and Internet Policy: A Proposal to the Ford Foundation; TRPC, Inc. Presents the 30th Annual Research Conference on Information, Communications, and Internet Policy: A Proposal to the Ford Foundation; CommLaw Conspectus - Where Internet Service Provides and Telephone Companies Compete: Guide to the Computer Inquiries, Enhanced Service Providers and Information Service Providers, Robert Cannon
  - Tides Center, 1998-2003 (Box 12, Folder 76)
    Grant Nos.: 9801148, 98011481 - Civil Rights Forum on Communications Policy: A Project of the Tides Center; A Proposal for General Operating Support (November 13, 2000); Draft Final Report to the Ford Foundation, Grant No. 980-1148-2 (January 7, 2002); correspondence; Civilrights.org printouts; mediachannel.org printouts; peopleforbettertv.org printouts; Civil Rights Forum on Communications Policy: A Proposal for a Supplemental Grant in support of a report and presentation: Case Studies of Local Action on Communications Reform in the Public Interest (April 19, 2002)
  - United Church of Christ (1 of 4), 1999-2000 (Box 12, Folder 77)
    Grant No.: 10000210 - Correspondence; Grant Proposal; Microradio Implementation Project press releases; Presentation - Making the Most of Your 100 Watts!, Michael D. Brown
  - United Church of Christ (2 of 4), 2001-2003 (Box 12, Folder 78)
    Grant Nos.: 10000210 and 10350845 - correspondence; The Microradio Implementation Project Final Report (January 29, 2002); microradio.org printouts; Filling Out the Non-Engineering Parts of FCC Form 318 or, How to Apply for a Low Power Radio Station, Directions for the First-Time Applicant; Technical Requirements for LPFM Station Operations and Guide to Filling Out FCC Form 318 Section V: Engineering Specifications; Low Power FM Equipment Guide; Application before the FCC on behalf of Calvary Chapel Wood River; United Church of Christ Office of Communication, Inc.: Proposal to the Ford Foundation for Support of The Media Empowerment Project (November 19, 2002); press materials
  - United Church of Christ (3 of 4), 2004 (Box 13, Folder 79)
    Press articles; correspondence; printouts from the United Church of Christ's website; Officer's Meeting Presentation - Office of Communications; pamphlet; Media Empowerment: A Guide to Understanding Media Power and Organizing for Media Justice in Your Community - Organizing Manual (English and Spanish)
  - United Church of Christ (4 of 4), 2006 (Box 13, Folder 80)
    Grant No.: 10500264 - correspondence; The Office of Communication of the United Church of Christ, Inc.: Working for Media Justice in the Digital Age - reports
  - University of Alabama (1 of 4), 2000-2001 (Box 13, Folder 81)
    Grant No.: 10150490 - correspondence; budget; Communication Research and Policy: A Critical View, Edited and with Commentary by Sandra Braman (May 24, 2001)
  - University of Alabama (2 of 4), 2001 (Box 13, Folder 82)
    Communication Research and Policy: A Critical View, Edited and with Commentary by Sandra Braman (May 24, 2001) - continued
  - University of Alabama (3 of 4), 2001 (Box 13, Folder 83)
    Communication Research and Policy: A Critical View, Edited and with Commentary by Sandra Braman (May 24, 2001) - continued; Sandra Braman cv; Mapping the Field: Media Policy and Technology in the 21st Century, Sandra Braman drafts; correspondence; Re-Visioning Information Policy, Sandra Braman; memos; press materials
  - University of Alabama (4 of 4), 2002-2004 (Box 14, Folder 84)
  - University of Illinois, 2001-2003 (Box 14, Folder 85)
    Correspondence; RobertMcChesney.com printouts; Illinois Center for Global Information and Communication Policy; Initiative on Communications, Culture, and Policy: A Pre-Proposal from the Institute of Communications Research University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign; First Draft - Summary and Recommendations of the Evaluation of Global Internet Policy Initiative in Central Asia (September 3, 2002); Islam in Africa and the Global Challenge: Reporting Islam in the US Media -Preliminary Proposal; Initiative on Communications, Culture, and Policy: Addendum; On the Study of Communication, The Institute of Communications Research, College of Communications, University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign; Strategic Plan: Framing Our Future, Occasional Paper Number 2
  - University of Maryland, 2000-2002 (Box 14, Folder 86)
    Grant No.: 10001436 - Developing a Public Telecommunications Service, Funding Proposal on The Ford Foundation; correspondence; University of Maryland Diversity Accountability and Implementation Plans at UMCP; Building the E-Commons; The Public Telecommunications Service; Community Information Corps (CIC) Phase I: The Summer of 2001 - Draft Version Two; White Paper: Civic Extension for the Information Age - Draft July 23, 2001; The Prince George's County Information Commons: A Proposal by The Democracy Collaborative; National Civic Review - Making Civic Renewal and the Commons of Cyberspace, Peter Levine; Can the Internet Rescue Democracy? Towards an On-Line Commons
  - University of Minnesota, 1999-2001 (Box 14, Folder 87)
    Grant No.: 10051181 - Attachments - Strategic Alliances in the Global Information Sector 1999-2000: A Proposal to the Ford Foundation, David Knoke; Office of Budget and Finance documents; Office of Institutional Research and Reporting website printouts; correspondence; Identifying Strategic Alliances in the Global Information Sector, 1989-1998, Anne Genereux and David Knoke; Implications of Network Structures for Managing Strategic Alliances in the Global Information Sector, David Knoke and Song Yang (April 2000); final narrative report
  - University of Oklahoma, 2002-2004 (Box 14, Folder 88)
    Grant No.: 10350266 - Citizens' Media Resources newsletter - Joint World Meeting, Ford Foundation (October 29, 2002); OURMedia: Initiatives toward strengthening a network of researchers and activists promoting research, dialogue, and a debate on citizen's media (November 19, 2003); pamphlet; OURMedia IV: Building Communication Societies (July 22-25, 2004), Porto Alegre, Brazil
  - University of Texas at Austin (1 of 3), 2001-2002 (Box 14, Folder 89)
    Grant Nos. 10250599; 10251194 - correspondence; Media Policy, Entertainment TV, and 'Race': Interrogating the Prospects for Change; Pre-Position Paper: The Positive Image Debate, Media Advocacy, and the Television Industry, S. Craig Watkins; "Ethnic Parity" in Entertainment Television: To Count or Not to Count; Discussion Paper for Media Policy, 'Race' and Entertainment TV Project Meeting, Saturday, February 9th, 2002; NCLR's Short History in Entertainment Television Advocacy, Henry Puente; All-American Girl: Producing the Asian American Family, Jane Chi Hyun Park; The Blueprint Imperative, Federico Subervi; DiverseTV: Why Not?, Dwight Brooks; Beyond the Digital Access Divide: Developing Meaningful Measures of Information and Communications Technology Gaps, Proposal to Dr. Margaret Wilkerson, Michael Oden
  - University of Texas at Austin (2 of 3), 2002 (Box 15, Folder 90)
    Correspondence; The TeleVisions Project: An Exploratory Project on U.S. Entertainment Television and Race, John D. H. Downing and Dr. Mary C. Beltran
  - University of Texas at Austin (3 of 3), 2004 (Box 15, Folder 91)
    Beyond the Digital Access Divide: Developing Meaningful Measures of Information and Communications Technology Gaps, Michael Oden (2 copies)
  - University of Washington, 2002 (Box 15, Folder 92)
    Grant Nos.: 10251189 and 10251178 (University of Pennsylvania) - Correspondence; Critical Cyberculture Studies: Current Terrains, Future Directions, David Silver (August 2, 2004)
  - University of Wisconsin - Madison, 1999-2001 (Box 15, Folder 93)
    Grant Nos.: 09901187, 1010510, 10100410 - Addition to proposal: revised budget; Linking Policy and Academic Research in Communication: A Proposal to the Ford Foundation, Lewis A. Friedland; grant status reports; correspondence; "Building Civic Capacity in Communication," 2000-01 Report to the Ford Foundation, Lewis A. Friedland
  - University of Wisconsin - Madison, 2002 (Box 15, Folder 94)
    Grant No.: 10100410 - statements; correspondence; Media Policy: Defining the Field for the 21st Century, Sandra Braman; Enriching the Field: Research and Education Collaborations in Media Policy, Sandra Braman - Drafts; Media Policy Education: The Gap between Curriculum and Need, Sandra Braman
  - Vanderbilt University, 2005 (Box 15, Folder 95)
    Arts Industries Policy Forum, The Curb Center at Vanderbilt - Background Papers, The Basics, Issue Briefs, Site Visits, Biographies, News, Notes, Meeting Summaries
  - World Association of Community Radio Broadcasters, 2004 (Box 15, Folder 96)
    Grant No.: 10401231 - Communique of the Seminar on Building Community Radio Broadcasting in Nigeria (October 20-22, 2004); Atelier pour l'elaboration d'une strategie nouvelle de suivi des activites et de lancement d'une campagne mediatique sur les activites de Amarc Senegal, Alymana Bathily; Informe narrativo AMARC-FORD; The Legal Framework and Environment of Community Radio Development: Case of Indonesia, Presented by Imam Prakoso (August 2004); AMARC Global Advocacy Project 2004-2005 Narrative Report
  - Yeshiva University, 2000-2002 (Box 15, Folder 97)
    Grant No.: 10050926, 10150439, 10251185 - correspondence; Proposal for "Digital Broadcasting and Civic Space: Focusing Public Debate"; Proposal for "Fostering Legal Scholarship, Research and Advocacy in Media Policy"; Technology and Standards in the Public Interest Comparing Values and Approaches to Code as Law Funding Proposal; Discussion Paper for May 12 meeting
- Conference Materials and Publications, 2000-2007; 2
  - Aspen Institute Forums and Conferences (1 of 3), 2001 (Box 16, Folder 98)
    Communications and Society Program publications - Sustaining Media Pluralism in Democratizing Societies: A Report of the Second Annual International Roundtable on Journalism and Freedom of Expression, Craig L. LaMay; Journalism and Emerging Democracy: Lessons from Societies in Transition: A Report of the Aspen Institute International Roundtable on Journalism, Craig L. LaMay; Reinventing Minority Media for the 21st Century: A Report of the Aspen Institute Forum on Diversity and the Media, America Rodriguez; Ford Foundation-Aspen Institute: International Roundtable Journalism and Freedom of Expression, Santiago, Chile: Summary Report Prepared by Jon Funabiki (March 13-16, 2001)
  - Aspen Institute Forums and Conferences (2 of 3), 2002 (Box 16, Folder 99)
    Communications and Society Program: Mission-Driven Media: Not Just Survival, But Success: A Report of the Aspen Institute Forum on Diversity and the Media, Titus Levi; The Aspen Institute Project on Humanities and Communications Technologies, Interpreting Culture and Communications Technologies: Exploring the Potential for New Approaches, Conference Readings, Tricia Kelly (July 24-27, 2002); Aspen Notes - 2002; Communications and Society Program: Participant Biographies: The Aspen Institute Project on Humanities and Communications Technologies: Interpreting Culture and Communications Technologies: Exploring the Potential for New Approaches (July 24-27, 2002); Brief History of the Aspen Institute
  - Aspen Institute Forums and Conferences (3 of 3), 2003-2007 (Box 16, Folder 100)
    Communications and Society Program publications - Democratic Enterprise: Sustaining Media and Civil Society, A Report of the International Roundtable on Journalist and Freedom of Expression, Craig L. LaMay; Next-Generation Media: The Global Shift, A Report of the Forum on Communications and Society, Richard P. Adler
  - Bellagio Conferences, 2006 (Box 16, Folder 101)
    "Collaborative and Networked Approaches to Global Communications Policy Research and Reform" Bellagio Study and Conference Center, Lago di Como, Italy (February 27-March 4, 2006) - drafts, Monroe Price; Towards a Lake COMO Alliance, "Collaboration of Media Research and Reform Organizations" - Draft Report of the Conference - Draft March 2, 2006; Annotated Bibliography - Media and Development; Annotated Bibliography for the Global Forum for Media Development by Ellen Hume (February 10, 2006); Agents, Policies, and the Internet in China, Boxu Yang; Why the Need for Global and Comparative Communications Policy Research Has Increased, Ashish Sen, VOICES, India; Approaches to Global Communications Policy Research and Reform, submitted by: Colin Sparks; African Collaboration for Global Knowledge: The Experiences of the Research ICT Africa! Network, Alison Gillwald; Essay for Conference on "Collaborative and Networked Approaches to Global Communications Policy Research and Reform", Bellagio, Willie Currie (February 27-March 4, 2006); Collaborative and Networked Approaches to Global Communications Policy Research and Reform website printouts - February 23, 2006; Biographies of Organizers and Participants; Towards a Survey of Media Law and Policy Advocacy Centers; conference schedule; participant list; correspondence; The Federal Institute for Access to Information in Mexico and a Culture of Transparency - Report for the William and Flora Hewlett Foundation (February 2006); Information for Conference Participants - 2006; A History of the Villa Serbelloni
  - Center for Digital Democracy, 2001 (Box 16, Folder 102)
    Correspondence; Center for Digital Democracy printouts; The Dot-Commons: A Virtual Tour of the Online Civic Sector
  - Center for Governmental Studies, 2002 (Box 16, Folder 103)
    Correspondence; Center for Governmental Studies website printouts; DemocracyNet printout
  - Contacts, undated (Box 16, Folder 104)
  - Conversations on Media, Technology, Society, and Culture: "Knowledge Building as a Grant Making Strategy in Media and Technology", 2002 (Box 16, Folder 105)
    Correspondence; Contact Info; Agenda; List of Presentations; Presenter Biographies; Informing Policy-making: Bringing the Research and Policy Communities Together, Sandra Braman; Mapping the Conditions of Media Expression; URL list; Presentation - Interest Groups and the Public Interest: Transnational Collective Action in Info and Communication Policy, Milton Mueller (November 7, 2002); The TeleVisions Project; Transcription of Audiotape - Conversations on Media, Technology, Society, and Culture (November 7, 2002); Conversations on Media, Technology, Society and Culture - Final Report, December 2002
  - Conversations on Media, Technology, Society, and Culture - Convening Report: Media and Communications at a Crossroads ~ The Role of Scholarship for Media Reform and Justice, 2007 January (Box 16, Folder 106)
  - Copyright and Digital Media in Post-Napster World, By Gartner, G2 and The Berkman Center for Internet and Society at Harvard Law School, 2005 January (Box 16, Folder 107)
  - Corporate Involvement Initiative, 2002-2003 (Box 17, Folder 108)
    Report on Grantmaking Related to the Business Sector, Rana Zincir (April 25, 2002); Ford Foundation Corporate Initiative - Market Workshop presentation (May 9, 2002); memos; New Directions in Grantmaking: Influencing and Leveraging Markets for Social Good, Michele Kahane, Rana Zincir, and Jennifer Powell (September 2003)
  - Documentary Filmmaking, 2004 (Box 17, Folder 109)
    Documentary in a digital era: A memorandum describing a report on the Ford Foundation's investment in documentary, 1980-2000, by Pat Aufserheide and Barbara Abrash (November 1, 2004)
  - Education, Media, Arts, and Culture Retreat, 2001 (Box 17, Folder 110)
    Agenda, Reflection Memos, Who's Who; Draft - The EMAC Statement: Toward a Program Vision and Rationale for the Education, Media, Arts and Culture Program (July 9, 2001)
  - Electronic Media Policy Portfolio Theory of Change, The OMG - Draft, 2005 (Box 17, Folder 111)
  - Freedom of Expression Working Group, 2002-2004 (Box 17, Folder 112)
    Memos; press clippings/research articles; Media Sustainability Index 2001; The Annual Survey of Press Freedom 2002; Intellectual Property Issues at the Ford Foundation: Proposal for a Report, Joe Karaganis; Scoping Study Proposal: Convergence of Communications Technology and Freedom of Expression; List of Current Subscribers; Ford Foundation Freedom of Expression Working Group History and Overview of Activities, 1999-2004; meeting notes (December 14, 2004)
  - Grantmakers in Film and Electronic Media - Media Policy Working Group, 2003-2007 (Box 17, Folder 113)
    Democracy at Stake?: Current Issues in Electronic Media Policy and the Future of the Public Sphere, A winter 2005 series of funders briefings, Hosted by the Ford Foundation; pamphlets
  - Institute of International Education Travel Grants (1 of 8), 2002 (Box 17, Folder 114)
    correspondence; International Women's Day 2002 - womensword.net website printouts; Hand Held Visions: The Impossible Possibilities of Community Media, DeeDee Halleck; correspondence regarding grant no.: 9800350; applications for Ford Foundation travel support; The World Summit on the Information Society website printouts (April 2002); "Modeling the delivery of interactive government and welfare services in an online environment," Sheizaf Rafaeli; reclaimthemedia.org printouts (August 2002); Creating the Illusion of Legitimacy, Civil Society Democracy Project, Computer Professionals for Social Responsibility
  - Institute of International Education Travel Grants (2 of 8), 2002 (Box 17, Folder 115)
    correspondence; applications for Ford Foundation travel support; Service Request Form Global Travel and Learning Fund; OURMedia participation in the World Social Forum, Porto Alegre, Brazil (January 23-28, 2003); Report on ISTAS 2002, Prepared by Becky Lentz; Narrative Report - Trip to the Digital Divide Syposium, Ford grant no.: 98003050; IAMCR/ICA Symposium on the Digital Divide (November 15-17, 2001) materials; Ford Foundation/University of Texas Project "Entertainment Television and Race," conference reports
  - Institute of International Education Travel Grants (3 of 8), 2002 (Box 18, Folder 116)
    Report for Ford Foundation on Computers, Freedom, and Privacy 2002, Prepared for Becky Lentz by David J. Phillips; Report on ISTAS 2002, Prepared for Becky Lentz by David J. Phillips; Conference Report by Alfonso Gumucio Dagron - Our Media Not Theirs II; OURMedia - Alternative Media Scholars and media organisations: What Role Can They Play; Report on the National Association of Latino Arts and Culture (NALAC) Conference 2002; "Reclaim the Media" Conference, Cascadia Media Alliance materials; Computer Professionals for Social Responsibility "Shrinking world, expanding net," - Conference Report to the Ford Foundation, Harvard, October 5, 2002; Global Congress on Community Networking the Digital Era, Montreal, Canada - Conference Report to the Ford Foundation (October 2002); Context, Identity, and Privacy in Ubiquitous Computing Environments - position paper (2002); Report on the Media Blackout Conference 2002; "Making the Invisible Visible": Poverty activists working to make their own media, Miranda Spencer (January/February 2003); Euicom Colloquium, Merlyna Lim; Report on Race in Digital Space 2.0; Report on Participation, Key Public Participants, The Internet Corporation for the Assignment of Names and Numbers (ICANN) Conference, Dorothy Kidd (November 2002); Final Report - Key Public Participants (KPP) at ICANN Conference, Marlyn Tadros; ICANN Meetings in Shanghai (October 2002)
  - Institute of International Education Travel Grants (4 of 8), 2003 (Box 18, Folder 117)
    2002-2003 grant information spreadsheets; applications for travel grant; correspondence; OURMedia participation in the World Social Forum; Critical Cyberculture Studies Conference (May 8, 2003) Agenda
  - Institute of International Education Travel Grants (5 of 8), 2003 (Box 18, Folder 118)
    Applications for travel grants; correspondence; Alliance for Community Media - Media and Social Change Workshop Presenters (July 9-13, 2003)
  - Institute of International Education Travel Grants (6 of 8), 2003 (Box 18, Folder 119)
    Correspondence; Conference Report, The Design Challenge of Pervasive Computing (Flow), Tom Klinkowstein - takeaways; Takeaways from the World Social Forum III
  - Institute of International Education Travel Grants (7 of 8), 2003-2004 (Box 18, Folder 120)
    correspondence; World Social Forum Conference Schedule - January 2003; A Summary Report and Reflection on Transforming Enterprise (January 27-28, 2003); AMARC 8, Elinor Rennie; The AMARC Conference in Kathmandu Nepal Report from Pete Tridish of Prometheus Radio Project; Report to the Ford Foundation: The 28th Annual Community Radio Conference (March 19-22, 2003); Bridging cyberlife and real life: a study of the online communities in Hong Kong, Anthony Fung; Crossing the Dark Bridge: The Reconstruction of Afghan Media, Tamara Gould (July 2003); Project Report - Media for Social Change: Alliance for Community Media (ACM) 2003 Pre-Conference Symposium and Conference Workshops; Narrative Report - July 29, 2003 Convening on "Reinventing Media Activism" Review Draft Report (2004); Networks, Activists, and Academics: Report to the Ford Foundation on TPRC Conference, Seeta Pena Gangadhran (2003)
  - Institute of International Education Travel Grants (8 of 8), 2003-2004 (Box 18, Folder 121)
    Technology Policy Research Conference (TRPC) 2003, Dharma Dailey; Telecommunications Policy Research Conference, Alison Brzenchek (October 2003); Report on TRPC 2003, Martha Wallner; Strategy Memo, Martha Wallner; TPRC Conference Report 2003, Inja Coates; My Experience at Next Five Minutes 4 (September 2003), Sue Beckwith; Internet Communication Technology Skill Shares on the Dalmatian Coast and the benefits of Human Computer Interaction design practices to non-profits, NGOs, and Open Source Software, Jeffrey Starin; Blocking Media Innovation: A Report, Jeffrey Starin; Conference Summary and Narrative Report, Edward M. Lenert; Gustavo Gindre Monteiro report; Listing of grants and grant recipients
  - Institute of International Education Travel Grants, 2005 (Box 19, Folder 122)